in a mercy protocol the state can be m
OE s or I initially all of the course
have the Block in the I state in their
caches when c0 reads it detects that
it's the only one who actually has a
copy of the block and because he's doing
a read it doesn't go into the modified
State it goes into the exclusive east
state the others keep the Block in the I
state when C one reads it detected it's
not the only one who has the block so it
normally goes to s state furthermore c0
now snoops another reader so it's no
longer exclusive and it moves to the
shared State - C - still has the invalid
state for its block when c2 reads it
also detects that there are two other
sharers so it gets the Block in the
shared state c1 nothing happens to its
shared state when we snow parade and we
are in the shared state we just stay
there because others reading is
compatible with the shared state c0 also
actually is in the shared state although
you were not asked to do this and now
finally when c1 writes because it was in
the shared state it will put an
invalidation request on the bus and once
it does that it can move to the modified
State
others see that invalidation request and
go to the invalid state pretty much
after a write we are always in the
modified state and all others are always
in the eye state at that point